Franklin Henderson

CONTACT

- math resume.fhwrdh.net
- franklin.henderson.pdf
- github.com/fhwrdh
- linkedin.com/in/fhwrdh

SKILLS

- JavaScript, React, Node
- **ᢖ** HTML, CSS
- Webpack, Gulp, Jest, etc.
- m npm, GitHub, GitLab
- {} JVM, Java, Scala
- C# .Net, C#
- SQL, NoSQL
- > XP, TDD, Pairing
- 中 Agile, Kanban, Scrum
- Y Leadership, Mentoring

USER GROUPS

- **WLVJS** Co-Organizer, Current
- Lunch.js Champion, Current
- S.LA, Current
- * ALT.NET, Dublin, 2009-2011

EDUCATION

- CSUN, Math
- Santa Monica College, CS
- College of Marin, CS

INTERESTS

- Brewing
- Photography
- **∠** Travel
- Music

ABOUT ME

A software professional with more than twenty years of experience building scalable, testable, maintainable systems across multiple technology platforms with a focus on UI/UX, testing, teaching, learning.

A proven history of leadership, both formally as an engineering manager / team lead / department leader and informally mentoring developers, other leaders and organizations on agile practices, test-driven development, project management, front-end technology, empathy, and user experience.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Manager of Software Engineering

CJ Affiliate

Feb 2018 - Present Westlake Village, Ca

Oversee a department of 40+ software engineers, coaching teams on execution, agile development, release planning, backlog management.

Work closely with Product Management organization on execution, prioritization, release planning, agile development.

Responsible for department-wide staffing including interviews, job descriptions, annual reviews, salary.

Principal Engineer / Team Lead / Front End Chapter Lead

CJ Affiliate

Jan 2015 - Feb 2018 Westlake Village, Ca

TEAM LEAD

Led a young, inexperienced, talented team through a difficult project with tight deadlines and an atrisk client. Took a rough prototype and delivered a high performance system for testing correctness and compliance of publisher websites. Scaled the system to a theoretical capacity of 500,000 tests per day. Full stack development, agile planning guidance, product demonstrations, customer engagement, team leadership, career mentorship.

Led a small team to modernize CJ's flagship front end application to ES6 JavaScript. Introduced a modern build pipeline based on npm, Gulp and Webpack.

FRONT END CHAPTER LEAD

Managed a department-wide group of developers and designers improving the quality and consistency of our front end applications. Provided guidance to the department on technologies, training, coding standards. Prototyped and introduced React as the department-side preferred technology for all front end applications. Oversaw development of the open source Visual Stack library of reusable React components.

PRINCIPAL ENGINEER

Developed an early prototype front end application used to demonstrate insights concept and explore requirements with customers and internal stakeholders. The application was featured prominently in the 2016 CJU Solutions Lounge.

Built an agile project management tool on top of Atlassian Jira to facilitate release planning and backlog management. Original intention was to plug a gap in the Jira toolset for a single team. The tool has grown and is now used company-wide to provide a data-driven snapshot of progress over time.

Senior Software Engineer

CJ Affiliate

Jan 2014 - Jan 2015 Westlake Village, Ca

Delivered a mobile SDK for event tracking in IOS applications. Developed and published a full IOS application containing the SDK to the App Store. This project required me to quickly learn Objective C and XCode.

Delivered a new Developer Portal allowing customers and third party developers access to the IOS and Android Tracking SDKs and created documentation on how to use them.

Principal Developer

Super Stealth Startup

Apr 2012 - Jan 2014 Thousand Oaks, Ca

Hired to built a next generation display advertising system. Designed, coded, tested an application that implemented complex rulesets across multiple advertising networks, user attributes and geographic configurations.

Implemented data migration tools to ETL ad server data into a reporting-friendly schema and an internal-facing, web-based application providing near-realtime KPls, impression statistics, CPMs, revenue. Node.js, CoffeeScript, MongoDB, Mocha, PostgreSql, MySql, AWS.

Principal Developer

TrueCar

Sep 2011 - Apr 2012 Santa Monica, Ca

Formed the nucleus of a new Internal Applications team to aggregate and modernize various legacy financial and internal business applications. Led the interview and hiring process.

Coordinated the successful upgrade and migration of existing Microsoft Dynamics GP server and 15+ client installations.

Introduced an internal-facing, web-based portal as a home for migrated and future interfaces produced by the team. Rewrote legacy financial application. ASP.NET MVC, Castle Windsor, NUnit, Rhino Mocks, MSSQL. Delivered multiple data migration applications compliant with the company's extensive data security policies.

Development Manager

Pocket Kings

May 2009 - Sep 2011 Dublin, Ireland

Assembled and managed a team responsible for multiple internal applications. Full stack development, devops, hiring, annual reviews, agile planning. Reported to CTO. .NET, C#, MSSQL.

Technical project management / leadership on key operations-focused development projects. Specifications, design documents, test plans, cross-team project coordination, demos.

Technical Lead

Pocket Kings

Mar 2005 - May 2009 Los Angeles, Ca / Dublin, Ireland

Built web-based customer service / business process application. Integrated with core game engine and multiple datasources and web services to support customer service, cashier, marketing/promotions, affiliate management, operations, fraud and game security. Initiated Domain Driven Design-based re-architecture of the application in response to the evolving enterprise architecture and business requirements. .NET, C#, WCF, MSSQL.

Initiated agile transformation within the IT organization. Hired the company's first ScrumMaster. Team success led to Scrum adoption across the company.

Senior Software Engineer

Movielink

May 2002 - Mar 2005 Santa Monica, Ca

Rewrote UNIX shell / Perl batch nightly jobs to populate data warehouse, adding error handling, logging, automation. Bash, Perl.

Developed rules-based royalty and commission calculator and features for Customer Account Management application. Java, ATG Dynamo, Oracle.

Software Engineer

Day Software

Oct 2001 - May 2002 Orange County, Ca

Created Java connectors to third party data sources from Day's flagship content management product, Communiqué Unify. Developed specs and code to connect Communiqué to IBM's Enterprise Information Portal. Worked closely with Day partners from Germany to develop the requirements and initial specification for an SAP connector. Completed initial implementation and started porting to JCA architecture.

Software Engineer

Post Communications / Netcentives

Oct 1999 - Oct 2001 San Francisco, Ca

Developed multi-threaded, distributed, high throughput email delivery system. Introduced and developed guidelines within the core engineering team for unit testing with JUnit. Java, JavaScript, Oracle, SMTP.

Created web-based monitoring tools for the operations team. Tools monitored system activity, performance, machine memory / CPU usage, and delivery schedule.

Software Engineer / Technical Lead

ModaCAD / Styleclick.com

Dec 1997 - Oct 1999 Los Angeles, Ca

Hands-on leadership of 4-6 member engineering team. Development, scheduling, hiring, project management, code review. Reported to VP of Engineering. Prototyped and evaluated technology for Styleclick.com e-commerce project. Eventually, the company pivoted and renamed to focus on this project.

Front-end development for a desktop CD-ROM product, sponsored by Intel and published by Sierra Home. Extensive use of early JavaScript and CSS integrated with IE4(!) and ActiveX.